BRIAN NGUYEN

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

TORONTO, ON CANADA

Contact

(416) 939 0448 duc25091999@gmail.com LinkedIn Portfolio

Summary

I am a full-time front-end developer with 2 years experience. Throughout my career as a software developer I've focused on developing scalable and well documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with projects on my own.

Skill Highlights

- JavaScript (ES6, React, Redux, Node.js)
- NextJs
- MongoDB
- Docker
- Git

- Typescript
- HTML/CSS
- MySQL
- AWS
- VSCODE

Experience

Front-end Web Developer - Nov 2021 - current **Hectagon Finance**

- Created the user experience that fetched, parsed, and formatted analytic data, and relayed it into React components.
- Working with other designers/developers using version control, bug tracking, and productivity apps
- Understanding of web-accessibility standards, UI/UX best-practices, cross-browser compatibility, general web functions and benchmarks
- Created documentation to teach new team members company standards and best practices in React.js and Node.js. This shortened learning time by an average of 16 days.
- Tested software for bugs and operating speed, fixing bugs and documenting processes to increase efficiency.

Fullstack Web Developer - Oct 2020 - Nov 2021 Alobase

 Created accessible, responsive, and functional user interfaces to allow visitors on any device to have the same perfect user experience.

- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks (ReactJS, NextJS), HTML5, and CSS3, which improved user satisfaction.
- Built API following RESTful standards to allow users to submit information by storing data in MongoDB.
- Developed applications using React while managing the State through Redux saving hours of users' time.
- Evaluate the current state of a website and provide recommendations for improvement

Education

Diploma Computer Programming - Oct 2018 - May 2020 Humber College, Toronto, ON, Canada